Finding Aid for Center for Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- U-Matic Videotapes 1971-1989
  - Undated
    - Undated Kathy Hoard (for Frank Yates), Orientation Tape: "Psych 100: Black Encounters," "AAS 203: Issues in Afro-American Development", 30 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Jim Ingram, columnist with the Michigan Chronicle, "On Attica, Media Influence, etc." Interview with Jon Lockard, 30 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Chokwe Lamumba, Republic of New Afrika (RNA), 60 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Claudia Morcom, Orientation Tape: "AAS 450/451, The Black Community and the Law", 30 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Paul Ramsey, Orientation Tape: "Survey of Afro-American Literature, 19th and 20th Century", 30 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Cedric Robinson, Orientation Tape: "AAS 409: Charisma and African Diaspora" and "AAS 501: Anarchism and Violence" "ten minutes each", 60 min (Box 37)
    - Undated Trotter House and Meridian Junior College Gospel Choirs, Parts I and II, 60 min each (Box 38)
    - Undated Godfrey Uzoigwe, "AAS 530, African History Agricultural Revolution to 1800", 30 min (Box 38)
    - Undated Zubena Memorial (Zubena reading poetry) a.k.a. Cynthia Conley d. February 1971, 60 min (Box 38)
  - 1971
    - 1971-03 Bethel A.M.E. Church Youth Choir. "Black Church and Music.", 60 min (Box 38)
    - 1971-03 Imamu Amiri Baraka, "Black Nationalism, Theater, and Blacks in the Media." Hill Auditorium. Poetry reading., 60 min (Box 38)
    - 1971-03 Imamu Amiri Baraka, "Discussing His School in Newark" and Jimmy Garrett, "On Education", 60 min (Box 38)
    - 1971-03 Jimmy Garrett and Phil Lee, "Problems of Black Educational Objectivity", 60 min (Box 38)
      (There is a reel-to-reel recording of Garrett and Lee on March 17, 1971 within the recorded sound -- reel to reel series)
    - 1971-03 Keorapetse William Kgositsile, Interview and Poetry Reading South African poet and activist, 30 min (Box 38)
    - 1971-03 Don L. Lee, "Black Perspectives" and a poetry reading. Michigan Union. a.k.a. Haki R. Madhubuti, 60 min. each (Box 38)
    - 1971-03 Don L. Lee, Blacks as artists, "Dynamite Voices," and Literature. Interview with Artee Young. AA Art Studio, 30 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-04 Al Loving, "On the Black and Abstract Art" (Interview), 30 min (Box 39)
    - 1971-05 Tony Brown, "Blacks in the Media" (Interview), 30 min (Box 39)
    - 1971-07 Fred Snowden, "Blacks in Athletics." Interview., 30 min (Box 39)
    - 1971-07-21 Kuumba Murals, "Dedication Ceremony for the Kuumba Murals at the Center for Afro-American and African Studies," Part I: Dances and Part II: Speakers (Jim Ingram, Tony Brown, Murry DePillars, Ken Blake), 60 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-09-21 Ken Cockrel, "Socialism, The Law," Part I Rackham Auditorium, 60 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-10 Morris Lawrence, "Afro-American Music and its African Roots" Interview. Washtenaw Community College. "45 minutes.", 60 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-10-25 Mardia Weebuweh, "African Wraps and Fashion Trends" "20 min." a.k.a. Dr. Mardia Harris-Stone?, 60 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-10-28 Rev. Albert Cleague, "Black Christian Nationalism." UGLI Multi-Purpose Room, 60 min. (Box 39)
    - 1971-11 Mildred Jackson of Eastern Michigan University, "Role of the Black Woman in Education" "30 min.", 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1971-11-11 Charles Thomas of the Black Economic Development League, "Community Organizing (Black Manifesto)" and "Demands of Reparations From Churches" Part 1 "38 min.", 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1971-11-11 Charles Thomas, "Black Manifesto" (Interview) Part II, 30 min. (Box 40)
    - 1971-11-17 Harold Neal, "Black Art" (Interview) "30 min.", 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1971-11-22 Gloria House and Jim Ingram, "The Media and Its Role in Oppression." (Interview), 60 min. (Box 40)
  - 1972
    - 1972-01-28 Preston Wilcox, "AFRAM" (Part I) and "Methods of Unity" (Part II), 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1972-02-20 "Annual Harold Cruse Symposium," Northeastern Illinois University, Center for Inner City Studies, 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1972-03-20 Lee Gill, "Arts of Black Folk" Black Cultural Living Unit "55 min.", 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1972-04 Sylvia Wynter, "The Culture of the Black Revolution" (speaking at the CLR James Conference), 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1972-09-19 Earl Lloyd, Interview with basketball players: Ernest Johnson, Ken Brady, Campy Russell, Henry Wilmore, Jon Lockard, 60 min. (Box 40)
    - 1972-10-20 "Black Education at White Universities," Parts I and I: Don Blackman, Chet Davis, Leonard Jeffries, Curtis Porter, Walter Stewart, James Turner, 60 min. (Box 41)
      ("Issues of Curriculum, and Direction for Standardization and Exchange Between Programs," Association for the Study of Negro Life and History (ASALH) Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio)
    - 1972-10-20 Don Blackman, Chet Davis, Leonard Jeffries, Curtis Porter, Walter Stewart, James Turner, 60 min. (Box 41)
      ("Black Education at White Universities: Issues of Curriculum and Direction for Standardization and Exchange Between Programs." Parts 3 and 4. Panel Discussion. "1 hour of 3 hours," ASALH Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio)
    - 1972-10-20 Cynthia Smith, "Religious Imagination in Afro-American Literature: Christian Paradigm and Artistic Complexity: Forms of Escape in Black Literature," Parts I and II, ASALH Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio, 60 min. (Box 41)
    - 1972-10-20 Cynthia Smith, "Religious Imagination in Afro-American Literature: Christian Paradigm and Artistic Complexity: Forms of Escape in Black Literature," Part III, ASALH Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio, 30 min. (Box 41)
    - 1972-10-21 Raymond Giles, "Separate Black Studies vs. Curriculum Reform", 60 min. (Box 41)
      (Comments: William Green; Presider: Parker, ASALH Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio "1 hour of 1 1/2")
      Also on VHS
    - 1972-10-21 "Blacks in Early Spanish History," Part I: Jack Holmes, "The Status of the Black Man in Spanish Louisiana" and Part II: Edna McKenzie, "The African in the Mexican Nation", 60 min. (Box 41)
      ((Comments: Edgar Love; Presider: Angela Gilliam), Cincinnati, Ohio "1 hour of 2")
    - 1972-10-21 "Blacks in Early Spanish History," Parts III and IV, Cincinnati, Ohio "1 hour of 2", 60 min. (Box 41)
    - 1972-10-30 Melvin van Peebles, "Cinema, Theatre, etc." (Interview), 60 min. (Box 41)
    - 1972-10-31 Fred Kwesi Hayford, 30 min. (Box 41)
      ((author of Inside America: A Black African Diplomat Speaks) (Former diplomat from Ghana interviewed by Phy Stevens, vice president director of the Howard Sanders advertising and public relations agency of Detroit))
    - 1972-11 Juanita Anderson, "Tribute to the Black Man, an Essay Toward Freedom", 30 min. (Box 41)
    - 1972-11-10 Eleo Pomare, "Seven Dances with Explanations and Discussion," Parts I and II, 60 min each (Box 42)
    - 1972-11-11 Eleo Pomare, "The 'history' of Eleo Pomare; Dance and Black Dance; The Black Artist (does he have a duty to Black society?" (interview with Vera Embree), 60 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-11-14 Julian Bond, "The Present Political Scene." Modern Language Building. Talk followed by questions, 60 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-11-20 U.U. Uche, "The Law and the American Family," Parts I and II, 60 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-11-20 U.U. Uche, Question period following "The Law and the African Family," Part III, 30 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-12-08 "Black Politics I," Part III, 30 min. (Box 42)
      (Panel Topic: "Political Theory and Political Action," Larry Moss, "Black Political Theory and Intellectual Context"; Elni Scott, "Threats to Pan-Africanism"; Dan Ah(?), "Ideology for Liberation" Atlanta, Georgia "1/2 hour of 1 1/2 hours)
    - 1972-12-08 Caribbean Literature: Haiti, Parts I and II: Carolyn Gerald, "Jacques Roumain, His Life and Literature" Atlanta, Georgia, 60 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-12-08 Caribbean Literature: Haiti, Part III: Carolyn Gerald, "Jacques Roumain, His Life and Literature", 30 min. (Box 42)
    - 1972-12-09 Avon Gillespie, "Sea Island Music: Black Games and Songs," Parts I and II "1 hour of 1 1/2 hours", 60 min. (Box 42)
  - 1973
    - 1973-02-02 Frances Cress Welsing, M.D., Psychiatrist Department of Pediatrics, Freedmen's Hospital, Ass. Prof. of Psychiatry, Howard University Medical School, "The Cress Theory of Color-Confrontation," Black Medical Association, "Community Health and the Emerging Black Physician: Bringing It On Home" Parts I and II, Rackham Auditorium, 60 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-02-03 Brenda Armstrong, "The Survival of Black Students in Medical School." Black Medical Association, Rackham Auditorium, 60 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-02-03 Nash and Satcher, "Black Identity and Dysfunctional Role Models," Black Medical Association, Part I, Rackham Auditorium, 60 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-02-03 Chamberlain, "Black Identity and Dysfunctional Role Models," Black Medical Association, Part II, Rackham Auditorium, 30 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-02-05 Malcolm Boyd (Interview by Jon Lockard), 60 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-02-10 George Shirley. Interview with Jon Lockard and Morris Lawrence, 60 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-03-14 Sylvia Wynter, "Rastafarians in Jamaica," Parts I, II and III (3 x 30 min.) (Box 43)
    - 1973-03-28 Sylvia Wynter, "Black and Brown Women", 30 min. (Box 43)
    - 1973-04-19 NCA-Contact Africa Dancers, "Local Dance Troupe under direction of Kojo Baiden", 60 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-06 Bertram Coppock, "AAS 100: Black Encounter," Orientation Tape, 30 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-06 Jon Lockard, "AAS 360/361: Arts of Black Folk" Orientation Tape, 30 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-06 Rovan Locke (Grad student), "AAS 412, "Black Politics in the USA, 1930-1972" Orientation Tape, 30 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-06 Milton Stewart, "AAS 465, Dynamics of Afro-American Music," Orientation Tape, 30 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-06-18 Rozaq Olopoenia, "AA 408, Africa's Economies in Their Social and Political Settings" Orientation tape, 30 min. (Box 44)
    - 1973-10 Trotter House Gospel Choir, 30 min. (Box 44)
  - 1974
    - 1974-01-18 Mustapha Muktarr, "Dalabani" Schorling Auditorium, School of Education (Box 44)
  - 1981-1989
    - 1981-10-10 "White Tribe of Africa: The Trekkers" Part II, BBC tv, 60 min. (Box 44)
    - 1983-02-11 Wade McCree, Nyema Woods, Al Morris, Rosa Parks, "Pioneers Night: The Civil Rights Movement in Retrospect: Looking Backward to Move Forward," Hale Auditorium, University of Michigan Business School, "Cassette #1," (Box 44)
    - 1983-02-12 Al Morris, Robert Brisbane, C.T. Vivian, "The Civil Rights Movement in Retrospect: Looking Backward to Move Forward", 120 min. (Box 45)
    - 1985-02-06 George Danns, Visiting Fulbright Scholar from University of Guyana, "Walter Rodney," Walter Rodney Memorial Lecture, 60 min. (Box 45)
    - 1985-02-06 Ron Walters, Professor of Political Science, Howard University, "Black Leadership: The Problem of Strategy Shift," Walter Rodney Memorial Lecture, 30 min. (Box 45)
    - 1987-02-23 Interview with Ali Masrui for UNICEF.("Backup Copy"), 60 min. (Box 45)
    - 1987-02, 1987-03 Forty-one news items concerning racism and racist incidents at the University of Michigan (Feb 6, 12, 19, and 20; Mar 1, 4, 5, and 6) Radio TV Reports, Inc. (2 x 60 min.) (Box 45)
    - 1988-01 Twenty-six news items concerning racism (January 11, 12, 13, 14, and 15), Radio TV Reports, Inc., 60 min. (Box 45)
      (Paper list enclosed in the plastic case.)
    - 1988-04-10 WXYZ-TV, "Second Look" episode concerning UM people and racism. "8:30 a.m.," Radio and TV Reports, Inc., 60 mins (Box 45)
    - 1988-05-10 "Frontline," "Campus Racism, 57 min. (Box 45)
    - 1989-03-02 UCAR Steering, Parts I and 2 (2 x 60 min.) (Box 45)
    - 1989-03-02 UCAR Steering, Parts 1, II and III (Box 52)
      ("transferred to VHS 3-4-93" (3 x 20 min.) The tape it was transferred to was damaged and discarded)
- VHS Videotapes 1971-2004
  - Undated
    - Undated "Commitment to Diversity" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Community Speak Out" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Cultural Presentations and Representations" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Decreasing the Gap" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Discourse in the African Diaspora: The Language of Musical Symbols," (Box 46)
      ("Good. Poor lighting.")
    - Undated Joe Dulin (Box 46)
      ("good, but first few seconds are not audible")
    - Undated "Ethnic Notions" (Box 46)
    - Undated Frameworks II (Box 46)
      ("Good Some background light -- sunlight so some poor visibility")
    - Undated "I'll Make Me a World" (Box 46)
    - Undated "LA: It Couldn't Happen Here," (Box 46)
      ("Good. Starts with baby crying in background so a little less audible at start,")
    - Undated Keefe Loraine (Box 46)
      ("good. Lots of snow at start. Skip for recording. Ends abruptly")
    - Undated "Million Man March " (Box 46)
    - Undated "MLK Day Discussion" (Box 46)
    - Undated "A Huey P. Newton Story" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Perspectives on Planning and Development" (Box 46)
    - Undated-Arnold Rampersad, First Annual Zora Neale Hurston Lecture (Box 46)
      ("Good sound but jumpy. Streaky especially at very end,")
    - Undated "Race Relations in Higher Education" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Recalling the Future: Art in Contemporary Africa" (Box 46)
    - Undated "Redefining Our Tradition," (Box 46)
    - Undated "The Retention and Performance..." (Box 46)
    - Undated UCAR, Dhoruba Bin Wahad (Box 46)
    - Undated UCAR Protest/Duderstadt New Coverage (Box 46)
    - Undated UCAR Steering Committee and History (Box 47)
    - Undated Dhoruba bin Wahad and Elmira Collins (Box 47)
      ("Recorded over tv show -- few seconds at beginning. Abrupt start. Very dark -- poor lighting. Switches abruptly to another meeting.")
    - Undated Washtenaw County C.V.P. (Box 47)
    - Undated "Women in Transition" Psych 201, 35 minutes (Box 47)
      ("Good but sound not very sharp on first speaker")
    - Undated South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) Visit to South African Universities
      - EEOC (Box 47)
      - London (Box 47)
      - Mandela (Box 47)
      - Radio Interview, "20 min. 55 sec." (Box 47)
      - Scenery Shots (Box 47)
      - University of Cape Town (Box 47)
      - University of Durban-Westville, 108 min. 30 sec. (Box 47)
      - University of Ft. Hare, 78 min. 58 sec. (Box 47)
      - University of Natal, Tape 1 100 min. Tape 2 64 min. (Box 47)
      - University of the North (Box 47)
      - University of Western Cape, 74 min. 22 sec. (Box 47)
      - University of WITS, 96 min. 19 sec. (Box 47)
  - 1971-1990
    - 1971-07-21 Ken Blake, Jim Ingram, Tony Brown, Murry DePillars, "Dedication Ceremonies for the Kuumba Murals" (Box 47)
    - 1972-10-21 Raymond Giles, "Separate Black Studies vs. Curriculum Reform" (Comments: William Green; Presider: Parker), 1 hour of 1 1/2 hrs (Box 47)
      (This exists on U-Matic tape as well. From the Association for the Study of Negro Life and History Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio)
    - 1978-10-11 Ben Scott, "Detroit's Hayden: America's Poet Laureate" re: Robert Hayden, Dubbed from Detroit's Black Journal (Box 47)
    - 1986-01 Black Forum, Jan-Apr, University of Michigan program (Box 47)
    - 1987-03 March 87 UCAR Protest/Duderstadt News (Box 47)
    - 1987-11-23 "For the Love of Baby Junkies" (Box 48)
      (documentary about crack babies; gift of the Hail sisters) CBC Documentary by Lorainne Hale?)
    - 1988-01-18 Harold Cruse, Benjamin Hooks, "Living the Dream," Oprah Winfrey Show (Box 48)
    - 1988-03-22 "Racism on Campus: Toward an Agenda for Action," Parts I and II, Governors State University, 2 videotapes VHS [TM] 90:48 and 72:23 (Box 48)
    - 1990-04-08 Robert Chrisman, "The Cold War vs. the Third World War," Women's Alliance for Nuclear Disarmament Ann Arbor Chapter (Box 48)
    - 1990-10-24 George Lamming, "Recording stopped close to end. Need to read on 4 HR LP 2" (Box 48)
    - 1990-10-25 George Lamming, King/Chavez/Parks Visiting Professor and Writer in Residence, "Culture, Colonialism and the Novel of Childhood," Residential College (Box 48)
    - 1990-02-02 -- Graduate Student Conference
      - Dr. Charles Henry, "Keynote" (Box 48)
        (marked 02/02/1990 in error)
      - "Racial and Gender," Session I (Box 48)
      - "To Be a Colonial," Session IIA (Box 48)
      - "Politics of Race," Session IIB (Box 48)
      - "Social Science," Session IIIA (Box 48)
      - "Community Self," Session IIIB (Box 48)
    - 1990-10-11 George Lamming, King/Chavez/Parks Visiting Professor and Writer in Residence, "Unfinished Journeys: A Reading," Rackham Amphitheatre (Box 48)
  - 1991
    - 1991-03-15/16 CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions, 1970-1990"
      - Earl Lewis, "Welcome" and Charles D. Moody, "Opening Remarks," "9:30-10:15 a.m." Tape 1 (Box 48)
      - Darlene Clark Hine, "Keynote Address: Establishing New Paradigms: The Creation and Growth of African Studies," "10:15-10:30 sic. a.m. 1 hour 59 secs." Tape 2 (Box 48)
      - Earl Lewis, Harold Cruse, Thomas Holt, Bazel Allen, Panel 1: "From BAM to CAAS: Origins and Aims of the Center for African American and African Studies, "10:30-noon" "Tape 3 (Box 48)
      - Moderator: Ronald Woods; Panelists: Earl Lewis, Michael Martin, William Daniel, Jr., Panel 2: "Models for Africana Studies," "1:30 -- 2:45 p.m." Tape 4 (Box 48)
      - Moderator: Bazel Allen; Panelists: George Davis, Barbara Ransby, Neil Foley, Panel 3: "New Curriculum Options," Tape 5 (Box 48)
      - Panelists: Abdul Goler, Stephanie Johnson, Roderick Linzie, Devlin Ponte, Day 2 Workshop 1: "The Next Generation of Scholars: Towards a Student-Centered Academy," Tape 1 (Box 48)
      - Moderator: Tracye Matthews; Panelists: Branda Flanagan, Jan Collins-Eaglin, Linda Chatters, Day 2 Workshop 2: "The Dynamics of Gender in Africana Studies and the Academy," "1:00-2:30 p.m." Tape 2 (Box 48)
    - 1991-03-16 J. Frank Yates, Arthur F. Thurnau Professor of Psychology, Closing Session: "Challenges for Future Development," CAAS 20th Anniversary-"Reflections and Revisions," "2:45-4:15pm" Tape 3 (Box 49)
    - 1991-06-24 Dr. Elsa Leo-Rhynie, "Status of Women in Jamaica," Jamaica Study Abroad. Center for Afroamerican and African Studies "121 min." (Box 49)
    - 1991-06-26 Connie Matthews Tabor, Black Panther Party, Part I (Box 49)
    - 1991-06-26/27 "Variety Show," Jamaica Study Abroad; and "A visit with Easton Lee," Jamaica Study Abroad (Box 49)
    - 1991-10-06 Teshome G. Wagaw, University of Michigan, Center for Afroamerican and African Studies. Another Ann Arbor / PSA's TV Show. Aired October 6, 1991. 28 mins. 28 sec. (Box 49)
    - 1991-11-15 Barbara Ransby, NBC Today Show, 7:45am (Box 49)
  - 1992
    - 1992 Panel 3: "Literary Perspectives," Second Annual Graduate Student Conference (Box 49)
    - 1992 M. Dawson, Panel 4: (Box 49)
    - 1992-01-20 MLK Day Symposium
      - Boggs, Carruthers, Laviera, Lumumba, "Redefining Empowerment: Unifying the Strands of the Black Struggle" (Box 49)
      - Muhammad, Okihiro, Vega, "Redefining Empowerment: Unifying the Strands of the Black Struggle" (Box 49)
      - "Native American Land Claims: Redefining America" (Box 49)
      - "Redefining Women, Race, and Class" (Box 49)
      - Henderson, Lagos, Mendoza, "The Future of Detroit: A Development Project" (Box 49)
    - 1992-02-14 Evelyn Higginbotham, CAAS Series, "Race, Culture and Politics", 1 hr. 28 min. 48 sec (Box 49)
      ("Front view. Camera person -- Dorcas Blue.)
    - 1992-02-14 Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, University of Michigan Law School, 2 videotapes VHS [TM] (Box 49)
      ("Front view. Camera person: Sue Hand. J.A. Hall, director and "Left view: Cameraman: Tony Burns")
    - 1992-02-16 Evelyn Higginbotham, CAAS Series, 1 hr. 30 mins. 27 secs. (Box 49)
      (Rackham Auditorium "Side view. Camera -- Tony Burns.)
    - 1992-02-18 Dr Lionel Jeffries, Black Student Union, 2 videotapes VHS [TM] (Box 49)
    - 1992-04-06 Pamela Crockett, "Rape in the Black Community," Baker-Mandela Center Campus Forum (Box 49)
    - 1992-05-15/16 Colloquium, "Race, Culture, and the Politics of Intellectual Inquiry"
      - Cornel West, "Los Angeles Rebellion: Reflections" (Box 49)
      - Houston Baker (Box 49)
      - Patricia Hill Collins (Box 50)
      - Roundtable Discussion (Box 50)
    - 1 1992-05-23 Susan Fair, Eric Jackson, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman, Maureen Taylor -- Michigan Survival Summit (Box 50)
      ("Original. Camera by Tobi Hanna-Davies")
    - 1992-05-23 Rhonda Sweed, Amy Jordan, Marian Kramer, General Baker, Michigan Survival Summit (Box 50)
      ("Original. Camera by Tobi Hanna-Davies,")
    - Undated Michigan Survival Summit: Health Workshop (Box 50)
    - 1992-10-11/12 "500 Years of Resistance: Political Prisoners", 2 videotapes VHS [TM] (Box 50)
    - 1992-10-11/12 "What's the Connection?" (Box 50)
      (Associated with "500 Years of Resistance: Political Prisoners"?)
    - 1992-10-14 "Genocide Then and Now," Baker-Mandela Center (Box 50)
  - 1993
    - 1993-01-20 Ahmad Abdur Rahman, Gloria House, Assata Shakur, Dhoruba bin Wahad, Freedom Forum, University of Michigan (Box 50)
      ((on tape label) The box contains the following, conflicting metadata: "Freedom Forum -- Detroit -- National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repercussion -- Dhoruba bin-Walad, Ahmad Rahman and Charlene Mitchell, 01/23/93" 1993-01-20 -- Ahmad Abdur Rahman, Gloria House, University of Michigan)
      ("raw)
    - 1993-01-20 Dhoruba Bin Wahad, University of Michigan, "raw," (Box 50)
    - 1994-02-02 Derrick A. Bell, "Keynote Address," "In Celebration of Black History Month 1994", 1 hr. 28 min. 08 sec (Box 50)
    - 1994-02-11 Opening Remarks, "Criss Cross Cultures," Parts I and II. Students of Color Of Rackham (SCOR) Conference, 120 min each (Box 50)
    - 1994-02-11 "The Power of Publications and Propaganda," Parts I and II, SCOR Conference (Box 50)
      (120 min each)
    - 1994-02-12 "Bodies and Minds That Matter," Parts I and II SCOR Conference, 120 min each (Box 50)
    - 1994-02-12 "The Race for Public Space," Parts I and II. SCOR Conference, 120 min each (Box 51)
    - 1994-05-08 "Hellshire Beach bus shots" and Verone Shepherd, "Historical Overview: Colonialism, Gender Roles, and Women's Resistance in Jamaica," Study Abroad Jamaica (Box 51)
    - 1994-05-11 Hermione McKenzie, "Reproduction, Family, and the Organization of Households: Class & Gender Relations in Domestic Sphere," Study Abroad Jamaica (Box 51)
    - 1994-06-09 "Student Interviews and Evaluations," Study Abroad Jamaica (Box 51)
    - 1995-03-04 "Literature," Panel 1: and "Closing Remarks," Students of Color of Rackham (SCOR) Conference, "Erasing the Disciplines" (Box 51)
    - 1995-03-04 "Racial Diversity in the Workplace" Panel 3, SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - "Artsource: Whose Tradition, Whose Body, Who's Bad?" Panel 5 SCOR Conference (Box 51)
      (Not dated (but presumably 1995-03-04)
    - 1 1995-03-04 "Teaching to Value Difference: A Part of the Solution" Panel 7, SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - 1995-03-04 "Policy Shifts" Panel 2 and Panel 4: "Re-Connections" (first half) SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - 1995-03-04 "Re-Connections: Hello, Culture Calling!" Panel 4 (second half) and "Brain and Brawn Enough: Work, Race, and Rights" Panel 6 (first half) SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - 1995-03-04 "Brain and Brawn Enough, Part II" Panel 6 and "In Space and Rhyme For Real: Hip-Hop, Double Dutch, Salsa, Jazz," Panel 8: SCOR Conference (Box 51)
  - 1996-2004
    - 1996-02-23 "Language, Consciousness, and Ethnicity," Panel 2 (10am -- 1pm), SCOR Conference, "Riptides and Undercurrent" (Box 51)
    - 1996 Friday East Conference Room Sessions, SCOR Conference (Box 51)
      (presumably 1996-02-23)
    - 1996-02-24 Renee Moreno, Keynote, Students of Color Of Rackham (SCOR) Conference (Box 51)
    - 1996-02-24 Afternoon Sessions, East Conference Room, SCOR Conference (Box 51)
    - 1996-02-24 East Conference Room Sessions, AM, SCOR Conference (Box 51)